Guide to the Tunisia Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Tunisia collection
1942-1988
MS 1547
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.75
(2 boxes)
The collection consists of printed material relating to political, economic, and social conditions in Tunisia.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator.
Associated Materials
African Collection, MS 605; African Postcard Collection, MS 1575; Pamphlet Collection, MS 1351. Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Arrangement
The material in the original accession is arranged chronologically. Additions to the collection may vary in arrangement.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of printed material relating to political, economic, and social conditions in Tunisia.
Tunisia -- Economic conditions; Tunisia -- Politics and government; Tunisia -- Social conditions; Bourguiba, Habib, 1903-2000
- Inventory, 1961-1988
  - Borguiba, Habib: presidential speeches, 1961-1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Habib Bourguiba was president of Tunisia from 1957 to 1987.
  - Progrès Économique, publication du Secretariat d'État au Plan et aux Finances, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Sabrah: a women's magazine, 1977 February (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - al-Nur al-riyadi: a sports magazine, 1977 May (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Newspapers, 1977-1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Political/general information magazines, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Agence de Promotion des Investissements: booklets, pamphlets, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Tunisia 1980: Main Indicators of the Economic Budget, Ministry of Planning (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Septiem Art: Revue de culture par le film, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Star Magazine, 1981 March 28 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - L'Avenir: Organe du Mouvement des Démocrates Socialistes (MDS), 1981 October 29 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Institute of Current World Affairs: newsletters, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Additional Material, 1942, 1943, 1952; Accession 1999-M-024
  Arrangement
  Materials are arranged chronologically.
  - Allied Post, 1942 December 24, 1943 January 23 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Tunis Telegraph: First British Paper in Tunisia, 1943 May-June (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Tunisia: Dangerous Separatism, vol. 1, no. 2, Editions France Actuelle, 1952 December (Box 1, Folder 3)